HARUKA OGINO

+64 21 2961842 • harukariq@gmail.com • Auckland, NZ • 🞧 https://github.com/haruka-ogino

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Having transitioned from civil engineering to software development, I have discovered a newfound passion for coding. My time as a civil engineer has allowed me to develop excellent communication, problem-solving, and time-management skills. I worked on major infrastructure construction projects, being fully responsible for multiple sites simultaneously. Most recently, I have been undergoing a full stack web development course at the Dev Academy. I have made projects using JavaScript and TypeScript alongside React, Express.js, and Knex SQLite3.

EDUCATION

NZQA Level 6 Certificate in Applied Software Development, Jan - May 2024

Dev Academy Aotearoa

- Intensive 17-week long course focused on full stack web development.
- Developed proficiency in JavaScript and TypeScript for front-end development, using the React framework.
- Gained experience in server-side programming with Express.js, and database management using Knex.js with SQLite.
- Implemented authentication and authorisation features using AuthO and JSON Web Tokens.
- Completed multiple projects in-class as well as personal ones, using frameworks outlined above, both collaboratively and independently.

Bachelor of Civil and Environmental Engineering (Honours), 2016 – 2019

The University of Auckland

- **Summer Research Scholarship** at the University of Auckland December 2017 February 2018 Worked under PhD candidate assisting in testing of old (singly reinforced) concrete walls.
 - Prepared wall panels for testing, set up and dismantle of equipment.
 - Calibrated testing equipment.
 - Assisted with testing cycles.

NCEA Level 3, 2015

Avondale College 2011 – 2015

- NZQA Spanish Scholarship 2015
- Australian Mathematics Competition Participant 2014
- Japan Exchange Trip 2014

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Women in Engineering Network (WEN) Mentoring Programme and Volunteering 2017 - 2019

Industry Chapter: - 2021 Mentor to a third-year civil engineering student.

- 2019 Mentee to a graduate civil engineer.

Student Chapter: - 2019 Mentor to a third-year civil engineering student.

- 2017 Mentee to a fourth-year civil engineering student.

Helped with events, such as charity bake sales, open-day stalls.

Unleash Space, Newsroom Writer 2019

- Wrote weekly stories for the website on events, upcoming activities, and ideas developed at Unleash Space.
- Helped at events as part of the Unleash Team.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jul 2023 – Jan 2024 Temporary Site Administrator

Leighs Construction

- Assemble QA (Quality Assurance) packages.
- Supply management and upkeep.
- Management of H&S (Health & Safety) documentation.

Oct 2022 – Jun 2023 Overseas Experience in Japan

- Language School Student
- I also worked while travelling as at a café, in a hotel, and as an au pair.

Mar - Sep 2022 Site Engineer

HEB Construction

- Production of H&S and quality assurance documentation.
- Daily organisation of worksite.
- Produced accurate site diary with quantities, to be used in monthly measures.
- Managed multiple sub-contractors simultaneously.
- Oversaw graduate engineers.

Jan – Mar 2022 Temporary Operations Administrator

Madison Recruitment for Meadowlark Jewellery

- Coordination of the jewellery making process, quality control and inventory.
- Cin7 project management.
- Assisted with packing and dispatch of orders.

Jul - Nov 2021 Geotechnical Engineer

Pattle Delamore Partners Ltd

- Carried out site visits to undertake ground investigations.
- Managed my time between projects both in-office and on site.
- Modelled ground profiles on several different software.

Jan 2020 – Jun 2021 Graduate Site Engineer

Fulton Hogan for Northern Corridor Improvements (NCI)

- Production of H&S and QA documentation prior to commencement of works.
- Daily organisation of multiple worksites; ground testing, land surveys, third-party testing and estimated daily quantities.
- Produced accurate site diary with quantities, to be used in monthly measures.
- Liaised with different disciplines to ensure sequence of works was followed.
- Managed design changes from the client on the footpath alignment.
- Lead my own worksites and crews by making decisions as unexpected issues arose.

Jul - Oct 2019 Student Engineer

Fulton Hogan for Glendowie Branch Sewer Upgrade

- Managed material take-offs and stocktakes.
- Executed environmental audits around the sites and hold points with designers.

INTERESTS

In my spare time, I enjoy studying Japanese, going for long walks with my dog and spending time with friends and family.

REFEREES AVAILABLE ON REQUEST